Guide to the Community Chest of Allegheny County Records, 1933-1960 AIS.1968.14b
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Campaign, 1942-1960; XI.
  There are documents relating to after-campaign analysis and evaluations designed to improve future fundraising efforts. Some of these include: The Community Fund campaign achievements list that contains goals, pledges, actual payments and shortfalls in campaigns of the 1930s and early 1940s, list of participants and campaign results for the City Neighborhood Division in 1944-1945. Volunteer reports discuss problems related to prejudice, and the failure of community organizing, human relations, and organizational structure.
  The Community Chest sought foreign language campaign volunteers through the American Service Institute. Included in the materials of the 1950s are census figures of the largest nationality groups in Allegheny County in 1953, as well as a list and description of 'key leaders' from the Polish Community.
  For the 1954 campaign, the Community Chest produced a brochure called, Court 1-6010,that described the available educational films created in Allegheny County through a Chest project that utilized local writers and actors. The films had titles such as "Incident on the Hill", "Nobody's Nothin", "Outcast", and "Stigma". The brochure and a list of television play dates are in Folder 9. Located in Folder 7, is sheet music titled, "Bright Red Feather", a campaign song by Maxfield Gibbons and John Gile (no date).
  Folder 10 contains materials from the 1950s related to the United Fund (United Way), including brochures describing the relationship between the Community Chest and the United Fund.
  - General, 1942-1951 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - City Neighborhood Analysis, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Clubs and Organizations Lists, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Group Solicitation, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Campaign Materials, 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - American Service Institute, Campaign Materials, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Materials, 1953-1954 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - American Service Institute, Campaign Materials, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Materials, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Campaign Materials, 1956-1958 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Social Agencies Section, Campaign Materials, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Social Agenices Section, Campaign Materials, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous, 1933-1959; XII.
  Miscellaneous materials from 1933 to 1959 include booklets, correspondence, income and expense sheets, lists, and reports. Included are budget analysis work sheets and agencies' income and expense sheets with figures from 1939 to 1944; correspondence relating to a community service exhibit at the Carnegie Museum in October 1950, called the Agency Come and See Show; Joint Plan of Merger of the Community Fund and United War Fund dated 1946; correspondence seeking participation in the Community Chest Thank You Week where agencies plan at least one event to thank friends and supporters; lists of Community Fund Agencies dated 1945 and 1953; the 1933 Articles of Incorporation for the Welfare Federation of Cleveland and a booklet explaining the services and history of the Cleveland Chest from 1913 to 1942; and correspondence from 1946 to 1959 generally concerning administrative issues at the Community Chest's office.
  - Application for Participation, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Changes in Agencies from 1939 to 1944, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Come and See Show, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - County Division Pledges from 1944 to 1946, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Community Chest Thank You Week, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Community Fund Agencies List, 1945-1953 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Merger, 1946-1950 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Policy Changes, 1937-1946 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Welfare Federation of Cleveland, 1933-1942 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Publications, 1948-1958; XIII.
  The series contains booklets and newsletters from 1948 to 1958 including one issue of The Chest dated December 1959; seven issues of Community dating from 1948 to 1951, published by the Community Chest, the Federation of Social Agencies of Pittsburgh, and Allegheny County; seven issues of Service from 1952 to 1958; and, two issues of UF Newsletter (United Fund) from December 1956 and November 1958. In addition there is a primer to the Community Fund agencies printed in 1953 explaining the services provided by each agency; and, a unified campaign plan specifically for companies that has no date.
  - Agencies Primer Giving Plan for Firms, 1953, and undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Newsletters, 1948-1958 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Annual Reports, 1941-1959; XIV
  Contains annual reports of the Community Fund for 1941, The United War Fund and the Community Fund for 1943, and the Community Chest Annual Report for 1959.
  - Annual Reports, 1941-1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1946-1956; XV.
  Contains clippings primarily from Pittsburgh area newspapers concerning annual campaign short falls as they relate to increasing requests for funds from agencies threatening service cuts to the community. Several of these articles focus on Community Chest funding problems in 1949, and the state of unified capital appeals.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1946-1956 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Schedule of Code Number Groups, undated; XVI.
  The series contains two bound, undated lists called, "Schedule of Code Number Groups". The lists link the Code Numbers discussed in the records to the Firm and Section Numbers of the Community Chest of Allegheny County.
  - Schedule of Code Number Groups, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)